Michael B. James

■ hello@michaelbjames.com | ↑ michaelbjames.com | ↑ michaelbjames | ▶ @lambdalinguist

Research Interests I am interested in Program Synthesis and Language Design. Programming Languages are an interface to express intent. I want to build systems and tools to help programmers, expert and novice alike, complete their task faster and safer.

Education University of California, San Diego

Ph.D., Computer Science, 2018-present.

Advisor: Nadia Polikarpova

Fields: Programming Languages, Program Synthesis

Tufts University

B.S., Computer Science, 2015.

Publications Digging for Fold: Synthesis-aided API Discovery for Haskell. Michael B. James, Zheng Guo, Ziteng Wang, Shivani Dosh, Hila Peleg, Ranjit Jhala, Nadia Polikarpova OOPSLA. November 2020.

> Program Synthesis by Type-Guided Abstraction Refinement. Zheng Guo, Michael B. James, David Justo, Jiaxiao Zhou, Ziteng Wang, Ranjit Jhala, Nadia Polikarpova 47th ACM SIGPLAN Symposium on Principles of Programming Languages (POPL 2020). January 2020.

Experience

Software Engineer II

Jana Mobile, Boston, Massachusetts, Feb 2017 - Jun 2018

Software Engineer I

Uber Technologies, San Francisco, Jul 2015 - Dec 2016

Elm Intern

Prezi, Budapest, Hungary, Summer 2014

Mentor: Evan Czaplicki

Teaching Graduate Teaching Assistant

UC San Diego, Fall 2019

Supervisor: Nadia Polikarpova

Course: undergraduate intro-to-programming languages course.

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Tufts University, Fall 2014 Supervisor: Kathleen Fisher

Course: undergraduate intro-to-programming-languages

2020

Digging for Fold: Synthesis-aided API Discovery for Haskell

Location: OOPSLA 2020 (virtual)

Talks

2019 Component-based Type Driven Synthesis

Location: University of California, San Diego